const nfpa211Chapter7QuizData = [
  {
    id: "7_1",
    question: "Masonry Chimneys shall be supported on properly designed foundations of masonry or reinforced Portland or refractory cement concrete or on noncombustible material having a fire resistance rating of not less than _________. (NFPA 211 7.1.1.1)",
    options: ["1 Hour", "5 Hours", "2 Hours", "3 Hours"],
    answer: "3 Hours"
  },
  {
    id: "7_2",
    question: "Individual Corbels occurring at any point within a masonry chimney shall not exceed _________. (NFPA 211 7.1.2.2)",
    options: ["1/2 the individual masonry unit height or 1/3 the thickness", "1/2 the individual masonry unit height or 1/2 the thickness", "1/3 the individual masonry unit height or 1/3 the thickness", "2/3 the individual masonry unit height or 1/2 the thickness"],
    answer: "1/2 the individual masonry unit height or 1/3 the thickness"
  },
  {
    id: "7_3",
    question: "Masonry Chimney Supports shall be permitted to be formed by corbeling from a wall that is not less than _________ in thickness to form a maximum total projection of not more than 1/2 the wall thickness. (NFPA 211 7.1.2.3 (1))",
    options: ["18 inches", "6 inches", "12 inches", "10 inches"],
    answer: "12 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_4",
    question: "If you are corbeling out from a 24 inch thick wall masonry chimney support, what would be the maximum length you could corbel out? (NFPA 211 7.1.2.3)",
    options: ["12 inches", "18 inches", "24 inches", "36 inches"],
    answer: "12 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_5",
    question: "If you are creating a masonry chimney support by corbeling, as long as the corbel projects equally on each side of the wall and the corbels do not project more than 1/2 the wall thickness, you can do this from a wall that is not less than 8 inches thick. (NFPA 211 7.1.2.3 (2))",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "7_6",
    question: "Corbeling used to change the direction of a masonry chimney shall have a maximum offset so that the centerline of the upper flue _________. (NFPA 211 7.1.2.4)",
    options: ["Does not fall beyond the center of the lower flue wall", "Does not offset more than 3 inches", "Is positioned horizontally", "Does not fall beyond the left side of the lower flue wall"],
    answer: "Does not fall beyond the center of the lower flue wall"
  },
  {
    id: "7_7",
    question: "Corbeling used to increase the chimney wall thickness is allowed to have a maximum total projection that exceeds the thickness of the chimney wall. (NFPA 211 7.1.2.5)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "7_8",
    question: "Where a flue is constructed of a single flue liner, how many sides should the flue liner be supported on using masonry? (NFPA 211 7.1.2.6)",
    options: ["1 side", "2 sides", "3 sides", "4 sides"],
    answer: "4 sides"
  },
  {
    id: "7_9",
    question: "A chimney flue shall not change in size or shape withing _________ above or below any point where the chimney passes through a combustible floor, ceiling, or roof components. (NFPA 211 7.1.3)",
    options: ["6 inches", "12 inches", "18 inches", "24 inches"],
    answer: "6 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_10",
    question: "Cleanout openings shall be provided in all chimney flues serving freestanding appliances. (NFPA 211 7.1.4.1)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "7_11",
    question: "The lower edge of a cleanout opening inside a building shall be a minimum of _________ above the lowest accessible floor level. (NFPA 211 7.1.4.3)",
    options: ["6 inches", "12 inches", "16 inches", "18 inches"],
    answer: "16 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_12",
    question: "The lower edge of a cleanout opening located outside the building shall be a minimum of _________ above grade, provided the cleanout opening is below the lowest chimney connector entrance. (NFPA 211 7.1.4.4)",
    options: ["6 inches", "12 inches", "16 inches", "18 inches"],
    answer: "16 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_13",
    question: "Cleanout opening and doors shall not be obstructed, nor should any combustibles be within _________. (NFPA 211 7.1.4.4)",
    options: ["6 inches", "12 inches", "9 inches", "18 inches"],
    answer: "18 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_14",
    question: "Cleanout doors shall be permanently marked with a message similar to 'Do not obstruct. Keep combustible material at least 18 inches away from this door'. (NFPA 211 7.1.4.6)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "7_15",
    question: "The base of the chimney flue shall start at a point at least _________ but not more than _________ below the bottom edge of the cleanout door opening. (NFPA 211 7.1.5.1)",
    options: ["6 inches but not more than 18 inches", "6 inches but not more than 12 inches", "2 inches but not more than 6 inches", "4 inches but not more than 12 inches"],
    answer: "6 inches but not more than 12 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_16",
    question: "Gaps between firestopping and the chimney shall not exceed _________. (NFPA 211 7.1.6.1)",
    options: ["1/2 inch", "1/16 inch", "1/4 inch", "3/16 inch"],
    answer: "1/16 inch"
  },
  {
    id: "7_17",
    question: "All spaces between chimneys and the floors and ceilings through which the chimneys pass shall remain fully open but be FIRESTOPPED with noncombustible material. (NFPA 211 7.1.6.2)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True"
  },
  {
    id: "7_18",
    question: "Firestopping of spaces between chimneys and wood joists, beams, or headers shall be of galvanized steel not less than _________ thick. (NFPA 211 7.1.6.3)",
    options: ["26 gauge", "16 gauge", "22 gauge", "24 gauge"],
    answer: "26 gauge"
  },
  {
    id: "7_19",
    question: "If 26 gauge galvanized steel firestopping is not used for spaces between chimneys and wood joists, beams, or headers, noncombustible sheet material not more than _________ thick shall be used. (NFPA 211 7.1.6.3)",
    options: ["1/4 inch", "1/2 inch", "1/16 inch", "3/8 inch"],
    answer: "1/2 inch"
  },
  {
    id: "7_20",
    question: "Thimbles shall be of fireclay or galvanized steel of a minimum thickness of 16 gauge. (NFPA 211 7.1.9.1)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "7_21",
    question: "Thimbles shall extend through the wall to, and 1 inch beyond, the inner face of the liner. (NFPA 211 7.1.9.2)",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False"
  },
  {
    id: "7_22",
    question: "Round chimney flues shall have a minimum net cross-sectional area of at least _________ the fireplace opening. (NFPA 211 7.11.3.1)",
    options: ["1/12", "1/8", "1/10", "1/6"],
    answer: "1/12"
  },
  {
    id: "7_23",
    question: "Square chimney flues shall have a minimum net cross-sectional area of at least _________ the fireplace opening. (NFPA 211 7.11.3.2)",
    options: ["1/12", "1/8", "1/10", "1/6"],
    answer: "1/10"
  },
  {
    id: "7_24",
    question: "Rectangular and oval chimney flues with an aspect ratio of less than 2:1 shall have a minimum net cross-sectional area of at least _________ the fireplace opening. (NFPA 211 7.11.3.3)",
    options: ["1/12", "1/8", "1/10", "1/6"],
    answer: "1/10"
  },
  {
    id: "7_25",
    question: "Rectangular and oval chimney flues with an aspect ratio of 2:1 or more shall have a minimum net cross-sectional area of at least _________ the fireplace opening. (NFPA 211 7.11.3.3)",
    options: ["1/12", "1/8", "1/10", "1/6"],
    answer: "1/8"
  },
  {
    id: "7_26",
    question: "Minimum Air Space Clearances for a Residential Exterior Chimney is _________. (NFPA 211 Table 7.2)",
    options: ["1 inch", "2 inches", "4 inches", "6 inches"],
    answer: "1 inch"
  },
  {
    id: "7_27",
    question: "Minimum Air Space Clearances for a Residential Interior Chimney is _________. (NFPA 211 Table 7.2)",
    options: ["1 inch", "2 inches", "4 inches", "6 inches"],
    answer: "2 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_28",
    question: "Liners shall be separated from a chimney wall by a minimum of _________ and a maximum of  _________. (NFPA 211 7.2.12.1)",
    options: ["Minimum 1/2 inch and maximum of 4 inches", "Minimum of 1/4 inch and maximum of 4 inches", "Minimum of 1 inch and maximum of 4.5 inches", "Minimum of 3/4 inch and maximum of 3 inches"],
    answer: "Minimum 1/2 inch and maximum of 4 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_29",
    question: "The maximum offset a liner / flue can have is no greater than _________ from vertical. (NFPA 211 7.2.13.2)",
    options: ["30 degrees", "45 degrees", "70 degrees", "15 degrees"],
    answer: "30 degrees"
  },
  {
    id: "7_30",
    question: "Chimney lining should not end less than _________ above the crown, splay, or wash. (NFPA 211 7.2.13.3)",
    options: ["2 inches", "6 inches", "12 inches", "4 inches"],
    answer: "2 inches"
  },
  {
    id: "7_31",
    question: "Where a single chimney has multiple flues, each flue shall be separated by a wythe. The wythe shall be at least _________ thick. (NFPA 211 7.2.14.2)",
    options: ["4 inches nominal", "4 inches actual", "8 inches nominal", "5 inches nominal"],
    answer: "4 inches nominal"
  },
];

if (!window.quizRegistry) window.quizRegistry = {};
window.quizRegistry['Chapter 7: Masonry Chimneys'] = nfpa211Chapter7QuizData;